不，求求你，发发慈悲吧。
No, please, please,
please, have mercy.
现在说什么都晚了。
It's too late for mercy now.
- 我们警告过你。- 我保证，
- We warned you.
- I promise,
只要你饶了我一命，求你了
if you just spare
my life, please.
一开始你说你毁了，
First, you say you're ruined,
现在你却想用钱摆平这事
and now you're trying to
buy your way out of this?
你这个肮脏的骗子！
You filthy liar!
你让我恶心。
You disgust me.
不，不，Tenax，我会给你钱的。
No, no, Tenax, I'll
get you your money.
- 干掉他- 不，不，不。
- Finish him.
- No, no, no.
- 拿走他的金子- 不，不，不！
- Take his gold.
- No, no, no!
罗马，曾经是文明的灯塔，
Rome, once the
beacon of civilization,
现在是一个腐败和腐朽的大水池。
is now a cesspool of
corruption and decay.
它的公民只关心两件事。
Its citizens are only
interested in two things.
面包和游戏
Bread and games.
他们叫我Tenax但那不是我的真实的名字
They call me Tenax, but
that's not my real name.
在罗马，生命毫无价值。
Life is of little value in Rome.
住在垃圾堆里，
Living in the muck,
在富人和权贵的阴影下
in the shadow of
the rich and powerful.
我在马克西姆斯马戏团的底层长大
I grew up in the underbelly
of the Circus Maximus.
总是饿着肚子，为食物而战。
Always hungry,
fighting for food.
但野心和努力让我成为了
But ambition and hard
work made me the owner
全罗马最大、最赚钱的博彩酒馆的老板。
of the biggest and most profitable
betting tavern in all of Rome.
在整个罗马。
In all of Rome.
我们做得怎么样？
How did we do?
刚刚超过8,000第纳尔。
Just over 8,000 Denarii.
- 这一批呢- 珠宝送给西班牙人。
- And this lot?
- Jewelry to the Spaniard.
把剩下的装起来。
Bag the rest.
如果你想在我的酒馆下注，
If you want to place
a bet in my tavern,
有四个赛马队
there are four
horse racing teams
你可以把你的钱，
you can put your money on,
绿色派、白色派、红色派和蓝色派。
the Green, White,
Red and Blue Factions.
驾！
Hyah!
他们的股份都被拥有了几百年
Their shares have all been
owned for hundreds of years
由罗马的贵族和元老院
by the nobility and
senators of Rome,
这给了他们难以想象的财富。
which gives them
unimaginable wealth.
但很快，
But soon,
这一切都将改变
all of this is about to change.
喂！这个还活着
Oi! This one's still alive.
- 过去的储蓄。- 不知道
- Past saving.
- Don't.
结束这一切，我求你。
End this, I beg you.
仁慈？
Mercy?
活着的比死了的更有价值。
Live ones are worth
more than dead.
仁慈是没有价值的。
No value in mercy.
当我时间允许的时候，
When my time allows,
我教孩子们他们需要知道的...
I teach the kids what
they need to know...
卡波，今天的货不错。
Carpo, good load today.
一些我不得不用艰苦的方式学习的东西。
Things that I had to
learn the hard way.
三十塞斯特斯买马。
Thirty sesterces for the horse.
十块给男人。
Ten for the man.
这个还活着
This one's still alive.
- 二十- 点三十分.
- Twenty.
- Thirty.
- 25岁- 完了
- Twenty-five.
- Done.
嘿，听着，伙计们，不管是死是活，
Hey, listen, men, dead or alive,
还是比马肉还不值
it's still worth less
than horse meat.
罗马皇帝尼禄结束了自己悲惨的生命后，
After Rome's Emperor Nero
took his own pathetic life,
一场血腥的内战随之而来。
a bloody civil war followed.
这一年被称为“四帝之年”。
This was called The
Year of the Four Emperors.
四位将军想成为
Four generals wanted to become
强大罗马帝国的统治者
ruler of the mighty
Roman Empire.
最后一个站着的人
The last one standing
是弗拉维乌斯·维斯帕西亚努斯将军
was General Flavius Vespasianus.
他的军队拥立他为皇帝后，
After his army had
made him emperor,
他重建了这座城市，
he rebuilt the city
and began at its center
建造一个新的巨型体育竞技场
to erect a new,
giant sports arena
安抚暴民
to appease the mob.
弗拉维安圆形剧场
The Flavian Amphitheatre.
沿着这里走...
Moving along here and...
维斯帕先皇帝出身卑微
Emperor Vespasian had
come from a lowly family
有两个儿子。
of mule breeders
and had two sons.
最年长的提图斯已经成为一位著名的将军，
Titus, the eldest, had
become a famous general,
图密善成了家族中年轻的政治家
and Domitian became the
young politician in the family.
他们被称为弗拉维安王朝。
They were known as
the Flavian Dynasty.
看哪，罗马最新的荣耀，
Behold, Rome's latest glory,
是我儿子提图斯征服朱迪亚的后代
born of my son Titus's
conquest of Judea.
我和罗马的士兵们一起分享荣耀。
I share the glory with
the soldiers of Rome.
为罗马的市民而建
Built for the citizens of Rome
在尼禄从他们那里偷走的土地上
on the same land that
Nero stole from them,
建造这座黄金屋
to build this Golden House.
比我想象的要小。
It's smaller than I expected.
你是游戏大师吗，马苏斯领事？
Are you master of the
games, Consul Marsus?
你是埃迪尔·鲁迪吗
Are you Aedile Ludi?
相信我知道群众想要什么。
Credit me for knowing
what the crowd wants.
马克西姆斯竞技场适合战车比赛。
Circus Maximus is
fine for chariot racing.
观众想看血
The crowd wants to see blood,
他们想离得足够近才能看到
and they want to be
close enough to see it.
我已经命令了成千上万的动物和角斗士
I've ordered thousands
of animals and gladiators
从帝国的每个角落
from every corner of the empire.
从我们北方的前哨
From our northern outposts
一直到我们努米底亚的省份
all the way down to our
provinces in Numidia.
是的，在我们还在等待这家企业的股票发行的时候。
Yes, while we still await the
offering of shares in this enterprise.
啊我重新考虑过了。
Ah. Well, I've
reconsidered that.
不会有股份。
There will be no shares.
马克西姆斯马戏团属于你
Circus Maximus belongs to you,
四个派系的股东
the shareholders
of the four factions.
但是这个竞技场，
But this arena will, instead,
属于所有罗马公民
belong to all the
citizens of Rome.
维斯帕先皇帝，提图斯，图密善，所有的弗拉维亚人，
Emperor Vespasian, Titus,
Domitian, all of the Flavians,
他们什么都不是
they're nothing.
一个骡子家族。
A family of muleteers.
这些弗拉维亚人威胁到了我们的生存
These Flavians, they
threaten our very existence.
宣称这个新的竞技场属于罗马的公民，
Asserting that this new arena
belongs to the citizens of Rome,
这不过是个策略
it's nothing but a ploy
来满足他们无尽的贪欲
to satisfy their own
boundless greed.
它会耗尽我们从马克西姆斯马戏团获得的财富
It will sap the wealth we
derive from the Circus Maximus,
也许更糟的是我们仅存的权威和尊严
and perhaps worse, what's
left of our authority and gravitas.
执政官，说吧。说吧。
Consul, out with
it. Just say it.
- 一步一步来- 号
- One step at a time.
- No.
一步也不能动。
Not one step at the time.
这不仅仅是阻止弗拉维安圆形剧场。
It is about more than stopping
the Flavian Amphitheatre.
这是为了阻止弗拉维人。
It is about stopping
the Flavians.
小心点，女人。
Careful, woman.
一个念头就能导致处决。
A mere thought can
lead to execution.
你难道不愿意冒这个险
Wouldn't you
rather take that risk
也不愿被遗忘
than be buried in oblivion?
也许我妻子是对的
Perhaps my wife's right.
如果换了皇帝
If a change in the emperor
意味着他和我们所有人分享
means he shares with all of us.
维斯帕先活不了多久了。
Vespasian is not
long for this world.
大儿子提图斯有责任感。
Titus, the elder son,
has a sense of duty.
但图密善呢？
But what of Domitian?
贪财的那个。
The venal one.
想象一下他坐在椅子上。
Imagine him on the curule chair.
如果他成为皇帝，
Were he to become emperor,
那我们所有人都完了
that would be the
end of all of us.
听好了
Listen up.
我们需要一些水。现在
We need some water. Now.
好.
Good.
15袋两百。
Two hundred for 15 bags.
上等黎凡特粉红盐。
Finest grade Levant pink salt.
茱拉别说了
Jula, stop it.
奥拉你就不能告诉妈妈吗
Aura, can't you
just tell Mother?
你想让我跟她说什么？
What do you want me to tell her?
我很无聊想离开这里？
That I'm bored and I
want to get out of here?
你迟早会的。
Sooner or later you'll have to.
继续走
Keep going.
去吧，姑娘。
Go on, girl.
我喜欢
I like it.
跳舞吧
Dance.
- 你听到了！- 求你了
- You heard me!
- Please.
求你了不请不要...
Please. No. Please don't...
不不
No, no.
我要杀了你们两个。
I'll kill you both for that.
但首先，让我们和你一起玩。
But first, let's have
some fun with you.
这是什么？
What's this?
她是我妹妹
She's my sister.
安静！
Silence!
你杀了一个士兵
You killed a legionary.
- 他喝醉了。她... - 他是罗马公民。
- He was drunk. She's...
- He was a Roman citizen.
这两个现在是罗马的财产。
These two are now
the property of Rome.
- 带他们来！- 不，不，不。
- Bring them!
- No, no, no.
茱拉茱拉
Jula... Jula!
不！不！不！妈妈！妈妈！
No! Mother! Mother!
快吃完
Finish up.
我女儿们给我做饭换换口味。
My daughters are cooking
for me for a change.
茱拉灵气！
Jula! Aura!
妈妈！
Mother!
妈妈！妈妈！
Mother! Mother!
卡拉，你要去哪里？
Cala, where are you going?
我要去找我的女儿们。
I'm going after my daughters.
你儿子呢，夸梅？
What about your son, Kwame?
他在打猎。
He's on a hunt.
我不能等他。
I cannot wait for him.
众神在向我们微笑。
The gods smile on us.
罗马人愿意出三倍的价钱买它
The Romans will
pay triple for that one.
他属于神阿培德马克
He is of the god, Apedemak.
恶魔会保护他。
Demons will protect him.
我父亲族人的狮神。
The lion god of
my father's people.
我们不能带走他。
We cannot take him.
罗马人可以对付神和魔鬼。
The Romans can deal
with the gods and demons.
带他走
Take him.
否则你什么都得不到，夸梅。
Or you get nothing, Kwame.
快点！快点！
Now!
请原谅我
Please forgive me.
住手，你们这些傻瓜！
Stop, you fools!
我告诉过你，
I have told you,
我可以把他们弄下跳板。
I can get them
down the gangplank.
稳住伊利亚你现在不在贝提卡。
Steady, Elia. You
are not in Baetica now.
他们是无用的。他们会伤害他们。
They are useless.
They will hurt them.
我可以做得更好。
I can do it better.
放下吧
Put it down.
我不需要什么暴发户西班牙人
I don't need some
upstart Spaniard
告诉我怎么做我的工作
telling me how to do my job.
我卸的马比你几天卸的还多。
I've unloaded more
horses than you have days.
我们的马再也不会被扔进那个该死的吊带里了。
Not one more of our horses
goes in that damn sling.
如果我是你，我会听我弟弟的。
I'd listen to our little
brother if I were you.
他知道马。
He knows horses.
我卸过犀牛。
I've unloaded rhinos.
你可以把大象卸下来。
You could have
unloaded elephants.
我不管
I don't care.
去他妈的让他们自己做。
Fuck 'em. Let them
do it themselves.
我有六艘船等着卸货。
I have six boats
waiting to be unloaded.
从埃及来的运粮船有消息吗？
Any word of the grain
ships from Egypt?
已经三个星期了，没有食物，
It's been three weeks,
and without food,
人们越来越焦躁不安。
the people are growing
more and more restless.
呃，可能今天到，也可能明天到。
Ugh, they might arrive
today, maybe tomorrow.
风暴向南。
Storms to the south.
一看到他们就通知我。
Send word as soon
as they're sighted.
稳住稳住就这样
Steady. Steady. That's it.
就这样
That's it.
好孩子容易.
Good boy. Easy.
就这样就这样
That's it. That's it.
罗马书第
Romans.
从埃及来的船被耽搁了。
Ships from Egypt are delayed.
没有谷物。明天再来。
There's no grain.
Come back tomorrow.
这是昨天的话。
That was the word yesterday.
我们已经三个星期没有粮食了。
It's been three weeks
since we had grain.
- 你听到我说的了。- 人们在挨饿
- You heard what I said.
- People are starving.
我们该吃什么？
What are we supposed to eat?
罗马无法给予它没有的东西。
Rome cannot give
what it does not have.
我没看到有参议员挨饿。
I don't see any
senators starving.
他们是最大的水蛭。
And they are the biggest
leeches of them all.
也许我们可以把我们的投诉
Perhaps we'll take our complaint
直接送到维斯帕西恩和他的幼崽那里
straight to Vespasian
and his pups.
去帕拉蒂尼！
To the Palatine!
去帕拉蒂尼！去帕拉蒂尼！
嘿，又有骚乱了。
Hey, there's another riot.
这次又是什么
What is it this time?
管他呢？走吧来吧伙计们
Who cares? Let's
go. Come on, guys.
去帕拉蒂尼！
To the Palatine!
去帕拉蒂尼！去帕拉蒂尼！
一起来！我们走！
All together! Let's go!
去帕拉蒂尼！去帕拉蒂尼！
To the Palatine!
去帕拉蒂尼！
去帕拉蒂尼。走！
Move to the Palatine. Go!
快，快！
Move, move!
为你的罪行付出代价！
Pay for your crimes!
快点！进去！
Quick! Inside!
关上大门！好了！
Close the gates! All right!
为你的罪行付出代价！为你的罪行付出代价！
Pay for your crimes!
来了
Come.
你笑着，因为他们要求你的血。
You laugh as they
call for your blood.
在神圣的尼禄皇帝统治下，每天都有骚乱。
Under the divine Emperor
Nero, there was daily rioting.
你弟弟在哪？
Where is your brother?
我猜是去操他的犹太女王了
Off fucking his Judean
Queen, I imagine.
他应该在这里。
Well, he should be here.
那帮暴徒要杀我们
That mob is out for our blood.
Good reason.他们饿了
Good reason. They're hungry.
只有禁卫军
With only the Palace Guard
和一个世纪的禁卫军
and one century
of our Praetorians,
我不知道我们能坚持多久。
I'm not sure how
long we can hold.
当你被围困在阿莱西亚时，
When you were
besieged at Alesia,
你用声东击西引开了袭击者
you used a diversion to
draw your attackers away.
你没有吗？
Did you not?
驾！驾！
Hyah! Hyah!
什么事？
What is it?
又是一场食物暴动，大人。
Another food riot, my lord.
皇帝计划一场比赛来吸引骚乱者。
And the emperor plans a
race to draw the rioters away.
为你的罪行付出代价！
Pay for your crimes!
罗马和平就到此为止了。
So much for Pax Romana.
你觉得一直都是这样吗
You think it's like
this all the time?
希望不是
Let's hope not.
今天有比赛。
There's a race today.
今天没有比赛。
There's not a race today.
你是瞎了还是白痴？
Are you blind or just an idiot?
看啊
Look at that.
让我们看看
Let's see that.
- 鼓- 我没聋。
- Drums.
- I'm not deaf.
天蝎座无处可寻。
Scorpus is nowhere to be found.
芬布里亚到处都找过了
Fimbria's looked everywhere.
我能猜到。我去叫他
I can guess. I'll go get him.
你们两个准备好下注。
You two get set
up for the betting.
慢点慢点
Slowly, slowly.
小心点
Be careful.
菌毛
Fimbria!
我们两天内都不应该比赛的。
We were not supposed to
race for another two days.
我们还没准备好。
We are not ready.
皇帝说我们比赛，我们就比赛。
When the emperor
says we race, we race.
天蝎座。
Scorpus.
嗨
Hi.
天蝎座？
Scorpus?
天蝎座。
Scorpus.
起来
Get up.
为什么？为什么？
Why?
别再吵了。
Stop that noise.
我们后天才比赛。
We are not supposed to race
until the day after tomorrow.
鼓声可能表明情况有所改变。
The drums might
suggest that's changed.
除非你开车，否则几乎没有人下注。
There's barely any betting
unless you're driving.
起来
Get up.
安东尼娅·塞维留斯，你的光临让我荣誉。
Antonia Servilius, you honor
such a place with your presence.
你要是敢对我指手画脚，我就把你眼珠子挖出来。
Look at me in judgment, I'll
have your eyes gouged out.
你和这东西的友谊降低了你的身份。
You lower yourself by
friendship with this thing.
马苏斯领事的妻子你老板？
The wife of Consul
Marsus. Your boss?
蓝色阵营的主人。
The owner of the Blue Faction.
她爱我
She loves me.
- 但为什么呢？- 就像我总是赢一样。
- But why?
- Same as why I always win.
- 因为我可以。- 即使是几百万？
- Because I can.
- Even hungover?
即使喝醉了。
Even drunk.
或许能让你清醒点。
Maybe that'll sober you up.
母亲爸爸要去哪
Mother. Where's Father going?
来吧
Come on.
- 是天蝎座！- 看是天蝎座
- It's Scorpus!
- Look, it's Scorpus.
- 你是对的- 快点.
- You're right.
- Hurry.
- 快点。-哦！
- Come on.
- Oh!
是天蝎座。
It's Scorpus.
- 去吧小心点去，装上，快。- 走吧快
-Go, careful. Go, rig it, quickly.
-Go. Faster.
哦，你是芬布里亚？
Oh, you are Fimbria?
我有一封来自伊斯帕尼亚贝蒂卡的介绍信。
I have a letter of introduction
from Hispania Baetica.
我们有十匹最好的西班牙种马。
Uh, we have ten Spanish
stallions of the highest quality.
我看起来像是从奴隶那里买马吗？
Does it look like I'm
buying horses from slaves?
呃，你们的皇帝让西班牙人
Uh, your emperor
made the Spanish
罗马公民，碰巧。
Roman citizens, as it happens.
听着，除非你是皇帝，
Look, unless you
are the emperor,
你可以滚了
you can fuck off.
巴克斯来了。
Bacchus has arrived.
哦，终于。
Oh, finally.
谢谢你，Tenax。
Thank you, Tenax.
天蝎座不比赛的时候下注就少了
Betting's light when The
Great Scorpus isn't racing.
那是天蝎座
That's Scorpus.
- 我的鞋呢？- 刚从牧场回来，
- Where is my bays?
- Just in from pasture,
- 被脊甲化了- 这对马不好
- being harnessed now.
- It's bad for horses
- 没有做好充分的准备。- 向皇上告状。
- not to be properly prepared.
- Complain to the emperor.
我会的
I intend to.
走开！
Go away!
你没什么好看的。
You have nothing to see here.
走开！
Away!
我看他没什么特别的。
He doesn't look
so special to me.
他有86匹马赢了。
He has 86 four horse wins.
是马在奔跑。
It's the horses that run.
你带走他的马，
You take his horses,
- 他赢的钱归我。- 他的女人归我。
- I'll take his winnings.
- And I'll take his woman.
快，快！
Come on, come on!
加夫罗斯，他怎么样？
Gavros, how is he?
他会好很多的。他今天早上跑了一趟。
He'll be much better. He
did a light run this morning.
快点，我们走。
Come on, let's move.
你疯了吗？来吧
Are you crazy? Come on.
开始
Incitatus.
你今天好吗？
How are you today, huh?
我漂亮的儿子。
My beautiful boy.
你尝过吗？
Have you tasted it?
当然了我还活着
Of course. I'm still alive.
- 所以呢？- 所以...
- So?
- So...
结构良好，有一点醋的味道。
Well-formed, with a
slight scent of vinegar.
太完美了
It's perfect.
- 他会跑得像风一样。- 好极了来吧，我们走吧。
- He will run like the wind.
- Excellent. Come on, let's go.
我们走吧，因西塔斯。来吧
Let's go, Incitatus. Come on.
第一声号角随时会吹响。
The first trumpets
are any minute.
这些是我最新的钻机。
These are my newest rigs.
很神奇，是吧？
Amazing, huh?
- 你说什么？不，不。
What? No, no, no, no.
这是...这是什么？
What is... What is this?
- 我们谈过了- 天蝎座的新装备？
- We talked about this.
- A new rig for Scorpus?
不我不记得了
No, no, no. I don't
remember that.
是啊，你可能喝醉了。
Yeah, you were probably drunk.
这双更轻转弯时更好
These are lighter,
better on the turns.
我们在他们身上花了一大笔钱。
We have spent a fortune on them.
福图纳有多少次喜欢我的旧装备？
How many times has Fortuna
favored me in my old rig?
去吧，得到它！
Go, get it!
你听到他说的了
You heard him.
把旧的拿来。走！
Get the old one. Go!
- 为胜利干杯。- 为胜利干杯。
- To victory.
又是你？
You again?
你们是什么人，间谍吗？
What are you,
spies for the touts?
我们只是想卖掉安达卢西亚人。
We're just looking to
sell our Andalusians.
我告诉过你，我不会
I told you, I'm not gonna deal
跟你和你的老马群在一起你说什么？
with you and your old nags. Huh?
安达卢西亚人？
Andalusians?
是的
Yes.
让我们看看
Let's see them.
来这边
Come, this way.
一共13只手，两条腿转，非常紧，
All over 13 hands,
two leg turns, very tight,
没有鞭子，像雪一样白色。
no whip and white as snow.
你是卖还是租？
Are you selling or leasing?
呃，卖东西。
Uh, selling.
你可是从西班牙远道而来。
You're a long way from Spain.
这些马对西班牙来说太好了。
These horses are
too good for Spain.
太贵了。
And too expensive.
我们想赚足够的钱在家里建一个养殖场。
We're looking to make enough to
set up a breeding farm back home.
- 两条腿转？- 是的
- Two leg turns?
- Yes.
比赛结束后我会和芬布里亚谈谈。
I'll speak to Fimbria
after the race.
天蝎座在比赛。
Scorpus is racing.
蓝派9比3
Blue Faction, 9-3 odds.
司机...
Driver...
天蝎座。
Scorpus.
所有这些都押白色赢。
All of these on White to win.
分散赌注。
Spread the bets.
这样明智吗你已经欠了这么多。
Is that wise? You
already owe so much.
我留你在这里是为了你的嘴和屁股。
I keep you around for
your mouth and your ass.
不是为了听你的建议。
Not for your advice.
你看起来很美，父亲。
You look magnificent, Father.
- 是吗？
Yeah?
我觉得自己像马粪。
Well, I feel like horse dung.
希望你是对的。
I hope you're right about this.
你叫提多来了吗？
Have you sent for Titus?
是的
Yes.
前几天，在我们参观弗拉维安竞技场时，
The other day, during our
tour of the Flavian Arena,
你透露了太多
you revealed too much
你是被自己的想法唤醒的
that you were aroused
by your own idea.
原谅我我
Forgive me.
控制我们的情绪是最重要的。
Control of our
emotions is paramount.
是的，父亲。
Yes, Father.
这一课也能让我哥哥受益。
A lesson that could
also benefit my brother.
- 是的- 尽管...
- Yes.
- Although...
也许我们应该为他和他的犹太女王走了而高兴
perhaps we should be happy
he's off with his Judean Queen.
如果他在这里，罗马的街道将血流成河。
Were he here, Rome's
streets would be a river of blood.
嗯.
Hmm.
神父，来点颜色？
Father, some color, perhaps?
- 颜色？- 在上脸颊。
- Color?
- On the upper cheeks.
号
No.
民众希望看到一个健康的皇帝。
The crowd wants to
see a healthy emperor.
颜色.
Color.
我希望这不会让你觉得绝望。
I hope this doesn't
reek of desperation.
给马苏斯领事让路
Make way for Consul Marsus.
让开
Make way.
领事
Consul.
鲁弗斯为蓝调做好准备
Rufus! Ready for the Blues
让他们的马被踢了吗
to get their horses
kicked today?
天蝎座和因西塔斯击败了白人
Scorpus and Incitatus
beat the Whites
连续三次
three times in a row.
我们的钱在氙气上。
Our money is on Xenon.
- 氙气氙气氙气- 天蝎座可以随时击败氙气。
- Xenon! Xenon! Xenon!
- Scorpus can beat Xenon anytime.
- 任何一天。- 让我们看看。
- Any day.
- Let's see about that.
- 你拿到了吗- 是啊
- Do you have it?
- Yeah.
从因西塔斯的马内。
From the mane of Incitatus.
像这样的，
With such as this,
我会看到一切。
I will see everything.
- 你想认识维克托？- 号
- You wish to know the victor?
- No.
他领先的那一轮。
The round in which
he takes the lead.
对其他人来说不可能，
Impossible for any other,
但对我来说，有了这个
but for me, with this,
福图纳会告诉我一切。
Fortuna will show me all.
福图纳笑了。
Fortuna smiles.
这匹马会赢
This horse will win,
在第二局领先
taking the lead on the second
到最后一轮。
to the last round.
你确定吗
Are you certain?
别侮辱我。
Do not insult me.
否则我诅咒你。
Or I curse you.
下一个
Next.
下一个是谁？
Who's next?
是的
Yes.
全押白色。
All on White.
给你，全押白色。
Here, all on White.
动下一个
Move. Next.
滚开鲁弗斯
Piss off, Rufus.
等你把欠我的钱还了再来
Come back when you
have the money you owe me.
我想下注。
I want to place a bet.
不能再赊账了。
No more credit.
你应该庆幸我没割开你的喉咙
Consider yourself lucky
I haven't slit your throat
呢
yet.
我有很有价值的东西要赌。
I have something of
great value to wager.
五百股蓝色阵营的股票。
500 shares of the Blue Faction.
- 你妻子的股份？- 不是她的。
- Your wife's shares?
- They're not hers.
她是我妻子，所以他们也是我的
She's my wife, which
makes them mine.
很大的赌注。
Very big bet.
你可以击垮我
You could break me.
Scorpus in the Blues赢得比赛
Scorpus in the Blues to win.
四比一。
Four to one.
大了大得多。
Big. Much bigger.
天蝎座在倒数第二轮比赛中领先，
Scorpus to pull to the front
on the second-to-last round,
赢得比赛
and win the race.
你想赌一轮吗？
You want to make a round bet?
你知道什么我不知道的吗？
Do you know something I don't?
你愿意打赌吗？
Will you take the bet?
如果不是，我去别的地方。
If not, I go elsewhere.
八比一。
Eight to one.
每股八千塞斯特斯。
8,000 sesterces per share.
完了
Done.
天蝎座在最后一轮领先。
Scorpus to take the
lead in the final round.
你明白吗？走了
Do you understand? Go.
35押白色。
35 on White.
我很紧张。两个塞斯特斯。
I'm tight. Two sesterces.
一个塞斯特斯。
One sesterces.
我比她更紧。
And I'm tighter than her.
三个塞斯特斯，我比他们俩都紧。
Three sesterces and I'm
tighter than both of them.
嗨
Hi.
图密善的性爱玩具在赌一大笔钱
Domitian's fuck toy is
betting an enormous amount
赌你赢
on you to win.
别玩了
Stop playing.
吃吧
Eat.
这有些出乎意料。
This was somewhat unexpected.
- 我几乎没有时间穿衣服。- 我听说了。
- I barely had time to dress.
- So I'm told.
或许你应该谨慎一点因为这有损我的尊严。
Perhaps a little more discretion
as it diminishes my dignitas.
容我提醒你亲爱的
May I remind you, my love,
你的尊严
that a good measure
of your dignitas
是从我的姓氏而来的
is derived from my family name.
我们不要忘记这一点。
Let us not forget that.
很难，因为你经常提醒我。
Difficult, given your
frequent reminders.
领事Antonia.
Consul. Antonia.
愿诸神再次眷顾我们。
May the gods favor us again.
我想他们会的
Oh, I expect they will.
安东尼娅，你怎么评价天蝎座最近的驾驶技术？
Antonia, how would you judge
Scorpus' driving skills of late?
他知道如何对待一匹纯种马。
He knows how to
treat a thoroughbred.
等等神父
Uh, wait, Father.
现在
Now.
听他们的
Listen to them.
在召唤我们的血之后。
So soon after
calling for our blood.
马苏斯领事的笑容很阴险
Consul Marsus
has a viper's smile.
是啊
Yeah.
朋友亲近，敌人更亲近。
Friends close, enemies closer.
伪装者更近了。
Pretenders closer still.
罗马的市民们！
Citizens of Rome!
我向你们介绍，选手们！
I present to you,
the contestants!
四个派系。
Four factions.
八辆战车和八个司机
Eight chariots and eight drivers
要么开车要么死
drive or die
走向胜利！
towards victory!
绿色队在失利后寻求胜利，
The Green seeking
a win after loss,
失去之后，失去之后！
after loss, after loss!
笑声使我们减少。
The laughter diminishes us.
但有埃斯塔修斯和阿维塔斯。
But there's Estasius and Avitas.
而红军呢，是被涂成红色
And the Reds, is it painted red,
还是最后一次看到的沉船上的血
or is it blood from the
last-seen shipwreck?
号那是酒
No. That was wine.
在白色派系中，
In the White Faction,
和宽袖车手氙一起
with Xenon, the
wide-sleeved driver...
氙气氙气氙气
Xenon! Xenon! Xenon!
爱斯普宁的阿多尼斯
The Adonis of the Esponine.
蓝军和寇科在后面擦屁股
And wiping up the
rear, the Blues with Kirko
还有伟大的天蝎座！
and The Great Scorpus!
我们走吧！
Let's go!
他的快马，从奥林匹斯山下来，
With his speed horse,
alighted here from Olympus,
伟大的因西塔斯
the great Incitatus.
不死不休！
Rise or die!
哇哦
Whoa.
至少你可以说你和大天蝎座赛跑了
At least you can say you raced
against The Great Scorpus.
战车准备好了吗
Chariots, ready?
比赛开始了
The race is on.
停止下注。
Betting's closed.
驾！
Hyah!
- 你看到了吗？- 他要毁掉至关重要的白色车。
- Did you see that?
- He's gonna destroy the vital White cart.
这可不够
It'll take more than that.
来吧！
Come on!
又来了
Here it comes.
驾！
Hyah!
哦，我的天啊！
Oh!
- 残骸- 船
- Wreck.
- Ship.
残骸！船！残骸！船！残骸！
Wreck! Ship! Wreck! Ship! Wreck!
- 我错过了什么？- 不多
- What did I miss?
- Not much.
快，检查滑轮！
Quick, check the pulley!
先清理基地！
Clear the base first!
请给我一张票.
One ticket, please.
提图斯将军
General Titus.
快去快去
Go, go, go!
离开赛道！
Off the track!
快去快去
Go, go, go!
天啊！你在干什麽？
Dear God! What are you doing?
天蝎座，现在！倒数第二轮！
Scorpus, now!
Second-to-last round!
- 父亲- 他们在我们的门口
- Father.
- They were at our gate
呼唤我们的鲜血
calling for our blood.
- 听我解释- 现在不行
- Let me explain.
- Not now.
很高兴见到你，兄弟。你错过了今早的好戏。
Pleased to see you, brother.
You missed the fun this morning.
是啊，我会搞定那些暴徒的。
Yes, well, I would have
taken care of the mob.
你不能用你的剑解决所有问题。
You can't solve every
problem with your sword.
他们需要食物来补充内脏。
They needed food for their guts.
- 不是内脏。- 快到了
- Not gutting.
- It's arriving.
- 明天就到了。- 你一直这么说。
- It's there tomorrow.
- So you keep telling us.
我最好还是招待他们
Better I entertain them
比你的军团士兵杀了他们还多
than your
legionnaires kill them.
安静点，
Be quiet,
现在
now.
- 天蝎座，现在！现在！- 天蝎座！
- Scorpus, now! Now!
- Scorpus!
容易.容易.
Easy. Easy.
快点！快点！
Now!
看看他的两匹马。
Look at his two center horses.
他们几乎不拉。
They're barely pulling.
天蝎座又是最后一名
Oh, Scorpus is last again,
也是他后来居上的一次胜利
and for one of his
come-from-behind victories.
也许这次不会
Maybe not this time.
驾！
Hyah!
Incitatus...
现在，因西塔斯，现在！
Now, Incitatus, now!
嘿！嘿！
Hey!
你对诡计百看不厌。
You never tire of the artifice.
技巧使它具有娱乐性
The artifice is what
makes it entertaining
而且有利可图
and profitable.
嗯，我更喜欢战场上的清晰。
Well, I prefer the
clarity of the battlefield.
你以为罗马不是战场吗
You think Rome
isn't a battlefield?
不，不，这是一个...这也许是个战场
No, no, it's a... It's a
battlefield, perhaps,
但没有明确的。
but one without clarity.
- 这让它变得更有趣。- 够了
- Which makes it all the more interesting.
- Enough.
冲，天蝎座，冲！
Go, Scorpus, go!
兴奋，更多。更多.
Incitatus, more. More.
更多.
More.
喔！
Whoo!
来吧！
Come on!
让那个狗娘养的看看你的厉害
Show that son of a
bitch what you're made of!
快点，快点！
Come on, faster!
啊！我的天啊！
Ah!
耶!
Yeah!
是的，我会的
Yes!
- 该死的天蝎座- 我的天啊！
- Fucking Scorpus.
- God!
该死的天蝎座
Fucking Scorpus.
我们的孩子，总是让人失望，不是吗？
Our boy, never fails
to disappoint, eh?
从来没有
Never.
- 父亲- 号
- Father.
- No.
- 神父，听我解释。- 后
- Father, let me explain.
- Later.
记住，当众表扬。
Remember, praise in public.
私下里的纪律。
Discipline in private.
天蝎座！天蝎座
Scorpus! Scorpus!
你今天输了。
You lost today.
只有钱。实际上，很多，
Only money.
Quite a lot, in fact,
但我赢得了更重要的东西
but I won something
far more important.
我在父亲眼里削弱了我哥哥的力量。
I weakened my brother
in my father's eyes.
- 你好- 嗨
- Hello.
- Hi.
- 你有空吗？- 当然了
- Are you free?
- Of course.
天蝎座！天蝎座！天蝎座！
Scorpus! Scorpus! Scorpus!
把鲁弗斯在蓝派的股份给我
Give me Rufus's shares
in the Blue Faction.
我们的耐心得到了回报。
Our patience has paid off.
- 等我一下- 是的天蝎座
- Give me a moment.
- Yes, Scorpus.
休息，
Rest,
在我的朋友埃莱加宝的怀里。
in the arms of
Elegabal, my friend.
你只是运气好。
You just got lucky.
运气是游戏的一部分。
Luck is part of the game.
柯克死了我又赢了一次
Kirko is dead and
another victory for me.
我该笑还是该哭？
Shall I laugh or cry?
- 把我的酒拿来。- 是的天蝎座
- Get my wine.
- Yes, Scorpus.
我们把哀悼留给别人吧。
Let's leave the
mourning to others.
我们应该庆祝一下。
We should celebrate.
那是什麽？
What is that?
财富，地位，权力，
Wealth, position, power,
和尊重
and respect.
全在那里面？
All in that?
五百股蓝色阵营的股票。
500 shares of the Blue Faction.
啊，又来了...再
Ah, here we go... again.
一个新的派系由一个卑微的平民贫民窟罪犯拥有。
A new faction owned by a
lowly, plebeian slumlord criminal.
- 无意冒犯- 没关系
- No offense.
- None taken.
一个天才的醉酒司机，
And a gifted drunken driver,
他既富有又受人尊敬
who has wealth and respect,
对权力和地位毫不在乎
and doesn't give a shit
about power or position.
无意冒犯，没关系。
No offense, none taken.
你不明白这意味着什么吗？
Don't you see what this means?
我把这些卖给出价最高的人
I sell these to
the highest bidder
我们就有足够的钱成立自己的派系
and we have enough
to start our own faction.
四个派系已经存在了几百年。
Four factions have existed
for hundreds of years.
贵族拥有它们。不是你和我这样的人。
Patricians own them. Not
the likes of you and me.
在这些日子里，
In these days,
什么事都有可能发生
anything can happen.
大家起立
Men rise.
我们的皇帝出身于一个养骡的家庭。
Our emperor is from a
family of mule breeders.
总有一天，像我们这样的平民也会统治这座城市。
One day, even plebeians
like us might rule this city.
当然了
No, of course.
我会成为神
And, uh, I will become a god.
不天蝎座需要喝一杯
No, Scorpus needs a drink.
你哥哥今天做得很好，你没有。
Your brother did well
today, you did not.
为了确保我们的公民不会饿死，
To make sure our citizens
do not starve to death,
或者站起来割断我们的喉咙
or rise up and cut our throats,
你的责任是保证我们的粮食供应。
your responsibility is to
ensure our grain supply.
风暴，或者没有风暴。
Storms, or no storms.
我不能控制风和潮汐。
I cannot control the
winds or the tides.
那你应该体谅他们，不是吗？
Then you should make
allowances for them, should you not?
- 是吗-是的
Yes?
你玩忽职守
You neglect your duty
睡在你床上的犹太女王
for that Judean Queen
who sleeps in your bed.
我告诉过你把她送走，但她还是睡在你的床上。
I told you to send her away,
but she still sleeps in your bed.
我想知道为什么。
I wonder why.
我来牵你的马。
Here, let me take your horse.
我的王后
My queen.
我来这里太鲁莽了。
It was reckless coming here.
我们的敌人认为她对你的影响太大了，
Our enemies think she has
too much influence on you,
我也这么想
and I think the same.
我打败了犹太人，
I defeated the Judeans,
把她和她的八万族人带到了罗马
brought her and 80,000
of her people to Rome
建造我们的竞技场。
to build our arena.
她和我同床并不代表她有影响力，
Having her in my bed is
not a mark of her influence,
这是他们失败和屈服的标志
it's a mark of their
defeat and submission.
他们还让孩子们超负荷工作吗？
Do they still
overwork the children?
因为你求情了，所以好多了。
It is better since
you interceded.
食物分配呢
And the food allotment?
还是不够
Still insufficient.
罗马人自己也不够。
The Romans themselves
don't have enough.
我们得到的所剩无几。
We get what's
left of very little.
你会为我们的被剥夺辩护
You would justify
our deprivation.
不，我只是想解释一下。
No, I only seek to explain it.
你的罗马将军怎么想
And what does your
Roman general think
关于我们被剥夺的权利
about our deprivation?
不管怎样，你都违背了我。
In either case,
you disobeyed me.
好吧，等我当上皇帝，
Well, when I am emperor,
我得自己做决定。
I will have to make
my own decisions.
不是什么时候，是如果！
Not when, if!
如果.
If.
不久我将渡过冥河
Soon I shall cross
the River Styx
黑暗王国
to the Kingdom of Darkness,
在此之前我得做个决定
and before I do, I have
a decision to make.
凯撒大帝
Julius Caesar
有这样一个选择，
had such a choice,
他选择了年轻的政治家屋大维
and he chose Octavian,
the young politician,
而不是那个士兵马克安东尼
over Mark Antony, the soldier.
结果是这样的，
And the result was this,
我们的帝国
our empire.
我宁愿选择士兵，
Now, I would rather
choose the soldier,
但我会选择
but I will choose
我认为对罗马最好的人
whoever I believe
will be best for Rome.
你明白我的意思吗？
Do you understand me?
好.把那个犹太女人赶走。
Good. And send the
Judean woman away.
我会考虑的
I will consider it.
女王陛下，快。我们得走了
My queen, quickly.
We must leave.
提图斯在路上了
Titus is on his way.
来吧来吧
Come on. Come on.
快点.快点.
Hurry. Hurry.
就这样了？
This is it?
没事没事这将是...
It's fine, it's fine.
It's going to be...
一切都会好起来的
It's going to be fine.
我的姐妹篇们。
My sisters.
- 夸梅- 你在这里干什么？
- Kwame!
- What are you doing here?
- 是我的错我- 不，是我的。
- It's my fault.
- No, it's mine.
- 我杀了一个罗马军团士兵。- 她在保护我。
- I killed a Roman legionary.
- She was protecting me.
快点，这边。
Quickly, this way.
你在那里！快点！抓住他！嘿，士兵。
You there! Quick!
Catch him! Hey, soldier.
- 不，住手！- 来吧
- No, stop it!
- Come on.
- 你在干什么？- 这是一个错误，先生。
- What's going on?
- This is a mistake, sir.
她们是我的姐妹篇。
They are my sisters.
她是在保护小家伙。
She was protecting
the little one.
这是极不公平的。
This is most unjust.
我为你打猎。
I hunt for you.
我为你们罗马人服务。
I serve you Romans.
把他也带来。
Bring him as well.
不，不，不！
No, no, no!
请原谅我女王身体不适。
Forgive me, please.
The queen is indisposed.
- 不舒服？- 是的
- Indisposed?
- Yes.
有什么事吗
Is there something?
我想为你展现最好的一面。
I wanted to look
my best for you.
你先出去
Leave us.
我当指挥官太久了
I am too long a commander
哪怕是皇帝的命令
for bristled orders,
even from an emperor.
他给你下了什么命令？
And what orders
did he have for you?
他让我把你送走。
He told me to send you away.
他说你有损我的尊严，
He says you
diminish my dignitas,
和家庭的责任
and that of the family.
他最好让他的儿子和继承人
He would do better to
grant his son and heir
自己做决定的权利
the right to make
his own decisions.
自己...
Myself...
或者图密善
or Domitian.
他威胁要选择图密善？
He threatened to
choose Domitian?
不是很明确，但是...
Not in so many words, but...
那你必须把我送走
Then you must send me away.
号
No.
你父亲横跨世界
Your father sits
astride the world
你哥哥在他耳边低语
and your brother
whispers in his ear.
如果他们想切掉你的蛋蛋，
If they seek to
cut off your balls,
我不会是那个把刀递给他们的人。
I will not be the one
to hand them the knife.
把我送走。
Send me away.
去矿场。
To the mines.
那些是锡矿的
Those for the tin mines.
竞技场的那两个。
Those two for the arena.
快这边
Quick. This way.
我需要更多的战士。
I need more of those, fighters.
角斗士，强壮的男人。
Gladiators, strong men.
他们在罗马建的这个新竞技场，
This new arena
they built in Rome,
他们是一条血河，我们是一片金钱的海洋。
a river of blood for them,
an ocean of money for us.
去矿场。
To the mines.
- 茱拉- 母亲
- Jula.
- Mother.
去锡矿。
To the tin mines.
儿子，告诉我这是个严重的错误。
Son, tell me this
is a terrible mistake.
- 对不起妈妈- 怎么会这样？
- I'm sorry, Mother.
- How did this happen?
他们不知道你为他们工作吗？
Don't they know
you work for them?
我试着解救我的姐妹篇们。
I tried to free my sisters.
- 你这个愚蠢的孩子。- 去矿场。
- You foolish, foolish boy.
- To the mines.
也许有一个办法
Maybe there is one way.
那个人正在整理
That man is sorting out
他们将作为角斗士被带到罗马
who will be taken to
Rome as gladiators
他将被派往克里特岛的锡矿。
and who will be sent
to the tin mines of Crete.
锡矿是什么？
What is the tin mines?
死刑。
A death sentence.
向他们展示你的战斗力。
Show them you can fight.
向阿佩德马克祈祷
And pray to Apedemak.
他们是巨人。
Those men are giants.
我见识过你的能力。
I've seen what you can do.
让狮子的心在你胸膛里咆哮。
Let a lion's heart
roar in your chest.
给他们看，不然就死定了。
Show them or die trying.
朱拉和奥拉呢？
What of Jula and Aura?
你的姐妹篇们也是。
Your sisters as well.
- 你们都得去罗马。- 怎么做？
- You must all go to Rome.
- How?
- 女人，出去！- 战斗.
- Woman, out!
- Fight.
- 你比你知道的要坚强。- 去矿场。
- You are stronger than you know.
- To the mines.
太短太小了。去矿场。
Too short and too
small. To the mines.
让他们战斗。
Let them fight.
停下来！
Stop!
我看够了
I've seen enough.
你在找竞技场，是吗？
You seek the arena, do you?
- 带他来- 如果我的姐妹篇们也来的话。
- Bring him.
- Only if my sisters come as well.
奴隶提出要求。
A slave who makes demands.
把他带来。
Just bring him.
那我就割断自己的喉咙
Then I will slit my own throat
我就不会这么做
the moment I am given a weapon.
带我看看你的姐妹篇们。
Show me your sisters.
啊
Ah.
在罗马的某个老色鬼那里能卖个好价钱。
They will fetch a good price
from some old lecher in Rome.
把他们也带来。
Bring them as well.
来了
Come.
- 回家吧管好我的事。- 你打算怎么办？
- Go home. Tend my business.
- What are you going to do?
奴隶是可以买的。
Slaves can be bought.
他们可以被买回来。
And they can be bought back.